Narrator: 1
Speaker: Here’s a solid gold piece of advice:
be wary of anyone offering you solid gold pieces of advice.
Narrator: 2
Speaker: The friend who advises you to, say,
stay in your relationship or leave your job may well be looking out for you,
but she’s inescapably looking out for herself, too.
Narrator: 3
Speaker: People will generally advise you to act more cautiously
than they would act themselves in a similar situation
– perhaps because they don’t want it on their conscience
if you take a daring leap and fall flat on your face.
Narrator: 4
Speaker: There’s a happy flip side to this, though, for parents, teachers, managers,
and anyone else who finds themselves in the position of needing to motivate others.
Narrator: 5
Speaker: This result isn’t all that surprising, I suppose,
when you consider how flattering it feels to be invited to give advice.
Narrator: 6
Speaker: Yet the truth, very often, is that we know exactly what we need to do
– we just lack the confidence to do it.
Narrator: 7
Speaker: To ingratiate yourself with someone,
it’s better to ask for a favour than to perform one:
the favour-doer will come to think of you as the decent
and likeable sort for whom they do favours.